<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>BioPython</title>
        <link>https://alleetanner.github.io/biopython/</link>
        <description>BioPython</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://alleetanner.github.io/biopython/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>• Further tools and resources</title>
    <link>https://alleetanner.github.io/biopython/posts/06scriptingtools/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Alastair Tanner</author>
    <guid>https://alleetanner.github.io/biopython/posts/06scriptingtools/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The bio package We used this command line package bio . As of late 2022, this is clean and streamlined set of command line tools for bioinformatics tasks. I appreciate that this is accompanied by a book which is paywalled but I will look into whether I can provide access for students. However, just the command line glossary is very useful, which you can install with
bio --download after this is downloaded, you can get (very succinct) definitions of bioinformatics terms, for example]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>• Alignments</title>
    <link>https://alleetanner.github.io/biopython/posts/05alignments/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Alastair Tanner</author>
    <guid>https://alleetanner.github.io/biopython/posts/05alignments/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Multiple Sequence Alignments Multiple Sequence Alignments are a collection of sequences which have been arranged to form a matrix with every sequence being the same length. This arrangement is usually done by insertion of gap. Each position along an alignment is an assertion of homology: we are expressing an evolutionary relationship between each nucleotide, codon, or amino acid (characteristics of the genotype). This is analagous to a trait character matrix, where our observations are on morphological, behavioural or other outcomes of gene expression (characteristics of the phenotype).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>• Input and Output</title>
    <link>https://alleetanner.github.io/biopython/posts/04inputandoutput/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Alastair Tanner</author>
    <guid>https://alleetanner.github.io/biopython/posts/04inputandoutput/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Input GenBank files Let&rsquo;s look at GenBank files, acquired on the command line or in Python. We will use a command line package called bio - see section 6 for more details on this package. Install bio in your terminal with
pip install bio we can see what bio can do by running the command
bio help we are going to acquire by accession number using bio, with
bio fetch XP_050796403 notice this command just blasts out the results to the terminal output, but we want this in a file!]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>• Sequence repositories</title>
    <link>https://alleetanner.github.io/biopython/posts/03repos/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Alastair Tanner</author>
    <guid>https://alleetanner.github.io/biopython/posts/03repos/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Sequence repositories While basic methods of sequencing have existed since the 1970s, it is in the 21st century that the field exploded. This was due to key technological advancements, collectively known as &ldquo;high-throughput&rdquo; or &ldquo;next-generation&rdquo; sequencing. Generating high-quality sequences, at a fraction of the price, made genomics accessible to even modest research groups.
The genetic revolution To illustrate this, sequencing a human genome in 2000 required many specialist research groups, several years, and $100 million dollars ; by 2010 this had dropped to a matter of weeks and $100,000.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>• Working with sequences</title>
    <link>https://alleetanner.github.io/biopython/posts/02sequences/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Alastair Tanner</author>
    <guid>https://alleetanner.github.io/biopython/posts/02sequences/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[BioPython&rsquo;s Seq class Seq is a class in the BioPython library - which means that we have both data (in this case, sequence information) and functions attributed to the object. Since those functions are part of a class, they are also known as &ldquo;methods&rdquo;. If this is confusing, don&rsquo;t worry too much! It just means that we can make special strings with Seq, and each also has special actions that can be done to it.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>• Set up and requirements</title>
    <link>https://alleetanner.github.io/biopython/posts/01setup/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Alastair Tanner</author>
    <guid>https://alleetanner.github.io/biopython/posts/01setup/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Anaconda and Jupyter Lab In order to provide a consistent interface, we will be using Jupyter Lab as our workspace. If you are familiar with other tools, such as PyCharm or VSCode, you are welcome to use these, but be sure you can also handle the specific requirements for your set up (ie, how to install packages and how to access the terminal).
If you haven&rsquo;t already, download Anaconda . Anaconda is a platform providing data science tools for Python and R.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
